Guide to the Ulysses Kay papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series VI: Professional Subject Files, 1941-1997
  - Music Exercises from University, 1942, 1951 (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - National Black Colloquium and Competition, 1978-1980 (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - National Symphony Orchestra--Commission, 1974-1976 (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Negro History Week Citation, 1967 February (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey Civil War Centennial Commission--Citation, 1965 (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - New York Philharmonic
    - General, 1980 (Box 95, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence and Contracts, 1989-1994 (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Notes--Miscellaneous Notes, 1975-1989, undated (3 Folders) (Box 95, Folder 10 to 12)
    (The last folder includes notes on Frederick Douglass)
  - Obituaries, circa 1969-1991 (Box 95, Folder 13)
  - Opera
    - General, 1960-1980 (3 Folders) (Box 95, Folder 14 to 16)
      (These files includes information on The Boor, The Juggler of Our Lady, Jubilee, and notations on other operas)
    - Agreements with Librettists, 1959-1966 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Business, 1974-1983 (Box 96, Folder 2)
      (Primarily related to Jubilee)
    - Commissions--Frederick Douglass and Jubilee, 1975-1989 (Box 96, Folder 3)
      (Includes additional material)
    - National Educational Television Correspondence, 1970-1971 (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Opera/South, 1974 (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Permissions
    - General, 1947-1972 (Box 96, Folder 6)
      (Includes permissions both sought by and sought from Kay)
    - The Monkey's Glue, 1977 (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1976-1977 (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Phoebus, Arise (Town Hall)--Reviews, 1959 (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Poems Copied By Kay, undated (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Press, 1969-1973 (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Press List, 1959-1968 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Pro Arte Chorale, 1976 (Box 96, Folder 13)
  - Program Notes
    (These are Kay’s notes written for his own works and programs)
    - A-P, 1957-1987, undated (Box 96, Folder 14)
    - Q-Z, 1954-1985, undated (Box 96, Folder 15)
  - Program Notes and Clippings, circa 1965-1988 (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 1 to 2)
    (Generally related to others)
  - Programs--Correspondence on, 1962-1991 (2 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 3 to 4)
  - Pulitzer Prize Music Jury, 1973-1979 (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Reading, 1980, undated (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Requests, 1975-1987 (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Rockefeller Foundation, 1979 (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Royalties, 1981-1983, 1990-1992 (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Royalty Statements, 1980-1997 (3 Folders) (Box 97, Folder 10 to 12)
  - Saratoga Performing Arts Center--Ormandy, Eugene (Philadelphia Orchestra), 1978-1980 (Box 97, Folder 13)
    (Includes correspondence and other materials related to the commission for Chariots)
  - Sigma Alpha Iota, 1970-1992 (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, 1963-1979 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Simple in New York--Correspondence and Script, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 3)
    (Script is by Langston Hughes)
  - Solicitations, 1973-1983 (2 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 4 to 5)
  - Song Literature, 1968 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Southeast Regional Metropolitan Orchestra Managers (SERMOM), 1974-1978 (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - St. Joseph Symphony, 1987-1988 (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Stephen Crane Set Corrections, 1966, undated (Box 98, Folder 9)
  - Student Work and Miscellaneous Notes, 1949-1981 (Box 98, Folder 10)
  - Sun Like Gold, 1970-1971 (Box 98, Folder 11)
  - Teaching, 1967-1968 circa 1980s (2 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 12 to 13)
    (The first file includes information about Kay’s appointment at Lehman College)
  - Texts, 1950s-1977 (3 Folders) (Box 98, Folder 14 to 16)
    (These are secondary texts, probably sources for Kay's works or texts that he was interested in for work purposes)
  - Timings and Text Sources, 1973, undated (Box 99, Folder 1)
    (For Kay’s works)
  - Tributes and Models, circa 1975-1990 (Box 99, Folder 2)
    (For others)
  - Trips to Italy and Yugoslavia, 1960 (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Ulysses Kay Week (Boston), 1988 March (Box 103)
    (Posters, clippings, and memorabilia related to the week honoring Kay)
  - University of Arizona Alumni Achievement Award (Commencement Program), 1980 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - University of Missouri - Honorary Doctorate, 1981 (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Urban League for Bergen County (Paul Robeson Award), 1983 (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Western Paradise, 1975 (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Who's Who in America, 1990-1994 (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Writers, 1971-1973 (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Xavier University / The Juggler of Our Lady, 1962 (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - Yaddo
    - General, circa 1968-1983 (2 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 11 to 12)
    - Annual Meeting, 1991 (Box 99, Folder 13)
    - Composers Applying, circa 1973-1980 (Box 99, Folder 14)
    - Report, 1970s (Box 99, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous Journal Pages, undated (Box 99, Folder 16)
  - Miscellaneous Professional Materials, 1953-1983, undated (Box 99, Folder 17)
- Series VII: Season Files and Other Clippings, 1941-1998
  This series contains clippings files related to Kay’s professional activities and performances of his works.
  - Subseries VII.1: Season Files, 1941-1989
    This subseries contains files that document Kay’s activities during individual performance seasons. The files include not only clippings, but also correspondence, information on programs, performance notifications, and reviews.
    - 1941-1944 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - 1947 (Box 99, Folder 19)
    - 1949-1952 (4 Folders) (Box 99, Folder 20 to 22)
    - 1953-1954 (2 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 1 to 2)
    - 1956-1957 (2 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 3 to 4)
    - 1963-1964 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - 1966-1976 (10 Folders) (Box 100, Folder 6 to 15)
    - 1976-1981 (5 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 1 to 5)
    - 1983-1986 (3 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 6 to 8)
    - 1988-1989 (Box 101, Folder 9)
  - Subseries VII.2: Other Clippings, 1949-1998
    These are more general clippings files that document Kay’s professional activities. They are arranged chronologically, and Kay’s grouping of materials into individual folders has been left intact.
    - General Clippings
      - 1949-1984, 1989 (3 Folders) (Box 101, Folder 10 to 12)
      - 1959-1998 (6 Folders) (Box 102, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Articles on Kay, 1969-1988 (Box 102, Folder 7)
    - Black Perspectives in Music, 1985-1990 (Box 102, Folder 8)
    - Special Programs and Notes, 1954-1982 (Box 102, Folder 9)
- Series VIII: Photographs, circa 1920s-1993, undated
  This series contains personal and professional photographs related to Ulysses Kay. The photographs are arranged chronologically.
  - Subseries VIII.1: Professional Photographs Involving Kay, 1940-1991, Undated
    This subseries contains professional photographs of Ulysses Kay. The photographs include portrait photographs, group photographs, and event photographs. The files are arranged chronologically, with unidentified and undated photographs being filed at the end of the subseries.
    - Kay, 1940 (Box 80, Folder 27)
    - Navy Band, 1940s (Box 80, Folder 28)
      (Negatives)
    - BMI, 1953 March (Box 80, Folder 29)
    - SCRA Judging Luncheon, 1954 May 11 (Box 80, Folder 30)
    - Kay at Stuyvesant Town (277 Ave. C), 1954 (Box 80, Folder 31)
    - Kay with George Szell, Director of the Cleveland Orchestra, probably 1954 (Box 80, Folder 32)
      (Kay's work was also performed by the Cleveland Orchestra in 1967; see Series III.1 Programs, 1954 and 1967)
    - Kay with Anahid Ajemian, Violinist, probably 1955 (Box 80, Folder 33)
      (See Series III.1 Programs)
    - Kay at BMI, 1957 December (Box 80, Folder 34)
    - 20th Century (Roosevelt Films), 1958 March (Box 80, Folder 35)
    - Kay with Gennady Rozdesventsky, Conductor of the Moscow State Symphony Orchestra, and Roger Sessions, Moscow, 1958 October (Box 80, Folder 36)
    - Kay and other Composers in the Russian Cultural Exchange at Taping of NBC Program, circa 1959 November 23 (Box 80, Folder 37)
      (Includes Slonimsky, Shostakovich, Amirov, Yerustovksy, Hanson, Shulman, Dankevich, Kay, Kabalevsky, Khrennikov, and Harris.)
    - Virginia Kay and Soviet Composers at Airport, 1959 November (Box 80, Folder 38)
      (Ulysses Kay is not in this photograph)
    - U.S. Embassy in Rome, 1959 (Box 80, Folder 39)
    - United Nations Recording Session, 1962 (Box 80, Folder 40)
    - Xavier University and the Premiere of the Juggler of Our Lady, 1962 (2 Folders) (Box 80, Folder 41 to 42)
    - Lincoln College Commencement (Honorary Doctorate), 1963 (Box 80, Folder 43)
    - Kay at Yaddo, 1963 (Box 80, Folder 44)
      (Photographs and Negatives)
    - Princeton Club, 1967 July 27 (Box 80, Folder 45)
    - Chicago Musical College Centennial Concert & Banquet, 1968 February 4 (Box 80, Folder 46)
    - Lake George Opera Festival, 1968 August (Box 80, Folder 47)
    - Illinois Wesleyan University (Honorary Doctorate), 1969 March (Box 80, Folder 48)
    - University of Arizona Commencement (Honorary Doctorate), 1969 (Box 80, Folder 49)
    - Kay at Piano, 1969 August (Ektachrome Color Slides) (Box 80, Folder 50)
    - Kay at Piano, 1969 August (Black & White Photographs) (Box 80, Folder 51)
    - US Civil War Centennial Commission--UK Receiving Centennial Medallion, 1960s (Box 80, Folder 52)
    - Kay and CBS Producer Oliver Daniel, circa 1960s (Box 80, Folder 53)
    - Kay, 1960s (Box 80, Folder 54)
    - University of Rochester, 1972 (Box 80, Folder 55)
    - Barbara & Ulysses Kay, 1975 May (Box 80, Folder 56)
    - 10 Year Club Lunch, 1975 (Box 80, Folder 57)
    - New York Philharmonic Reception, 1977 (Box 80, Folder 58)
    - BMI Student Composer Awards, 1978 May 11 (Box 80, Folder 59)
    - Dickinson College, 1978 May (Box 80, Folder 60)
    - Kay with Dana Forley in Class, 1979 December (Box 80, Folder 61)
    - Unidentified Photographs taken by Mary Gail Walker, circa 1979 (Box 80, Folder 61a)
    - Kay at Home in Englewood, New Jersey, circa 1970s (Box 80, Folder 62)
    - Photographs, circa 1970s (Box 80, Folder 63)
    - University of Arizona Commencement, 1980 (Box 80, Folder 64)
    - Kay, circa 1980 (Box 80, Folder 65)
    - University of Kansas City, Missouri (Honorary Doctorate), 1981 November (Box 80, Folder 66)
    - Reception for Chinese, 1981 (Box 80, Folder 67)
    - National Association of Negro Musicians Dinner, 1983 August 18 (Box 80, Folder 68)
    - Houston Ballet, 1984 (Box 80, Folder 69)
    - BMI Awards, 1985 May 16 (Box 80, Folder 70)
      (Includes press release. Kay awarded a citation.)
    - [BMI] Student Composers Judging, 1984 April 7 (Box 80, Folder 71)
    - Kay, Tom Everett, and Bob Gibson in Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1988 March 12 (Box 80, Folder 72)
    - Wayne Chamber Orchestra (New Jersey), 1989 (Box 80, Folder 73)
    - Lehman College Tribute Concert, 1989 (Box 80, Folder 74)
    - Unidentified Event, 1991 May 10 (Box 80, Folder 75)
    - Kay with Elsie Bennett (Accordion), undated (Box 80, Folder 76)
    - Kay with Stan Meyers, undated (Box 80, Folder 77)
    - Kay with Dr. Gene-Ann Polk Horne, undated (Box 80, Folder 78)
    - Various Portrait Photographs, undated (Box 80, Folder 79)
    - Unidentified Photographs by H.Y. Reiter (BMI), undated (Box 80, Folder 80)
    - Unidentified UK Professional Photographs, undated, (2 Folders) (Box 80, Folder 81 to 82)
  - Subseries VIII.2: Other Professional Photographs, circa 1940s-1993, undated
    This subseries contains photographs of others that are related to Kay’s professional activities. The photographs are primarily portrait photographs of performers.
    - 3 Photographs found in "5 Mosaics" (1940), undated (Includes inscribed photographs of Leon Kirkpatrick and a signed photo of "Minnette") (Box 80, Folder 83)
    - Yaddo (Postcards), circa 1950s (Box 80, Folder 83a)
    - United States Marine Band, 1958-1960 (Box 80, Folder 84)
    - David Mearns looking at a Kay Manuscript, 1962 (Box 80, Folder 85)
    - Oscar Petty, 1993 (Box 80, Folder 86)
      (Inscribed to Kay)
    - Hale Smith, undated (Box 80, Folder 87)
    - Paul Barbarin, Undated (Box 80, Folder 88)
      (This is a picture of Barbarin with King Oliver’s Dixie Syncopators, undated. It is not an original photograph, but a published copy that included text on Barbarin.)
    - Unidentified Dance Photo, undated (Box 80, Folder 89)
  - Subseries VIII.3: Family and Personal Photographs, 1920s-1990, undated
    This subseries contains primarily family photographs, although there are also some personal photographs taken in Holland, Russia, and of unidentified acquaintances. Most of the photographs are unidentified
    - Early Family Photographs, 1920s (Box 80, Folder 90)
    - Friends and Others (Unidentified), 1940s & 1950s undated (Box 80, Folder 91)
    - Ulysses Kay and Less Roehy, 1940s (Box 80, Folder 92)
    - Kays at Academy [of Rome], circa 1949 (Box 80, Folder 93)
      (Includes related 1995 condolence letter)
    - Ulysses and Barbara Kay, circa 1950 (Box 80, Folder 94)
    - Virginia Kay, 1951 (With related correspondence (1963 1973) and a birth announcement) (Box 80, Folder 95)
    - Elizabeth Davis Kay, circa 1950s (Box 80, Folder 96)
    - Moscow, circa 1958 (Box 80, Folder 97)
      (Photographs and negatives)
    - Kay Family Photographs, Miscellaneous, 1950s-1960s (6 Folders) (Box 81, Folder 1 to 6)
    - Kay Family Photographs, Miscellaneous, 1970s (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Kay Family Photographs, Miscellaneous Negatives, 1950s-1970s (3 Folders) (Box 81, Folder 8 to 10)
    - Ulysses and Barbara Kay, circa 1990 (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Holland--Acad (Angello), Ballet, and Others, undated (Negatives) (Box 81, Folder 12)
- Series IX: Audiovisual Materials, 1947-1988 undated
  This series contains audio and video primarily related to Kay’s professional life. The materials include U-Matic video, film reels, audio reels, audio cassettes, commercially-issued phonograph records, and acetate discs.
  - Subseries IX.1: Audio Recordings, 1947-1988 undated
    The majority of this subseries consists of recordings of performances of Kay’s works, but there are also some interviews, lectures, talks, and music used in television and commercials.
    - "4 Contemporary Choral Works" King’s Chapel Choir of Boston and Cambridge Festival Strings, recorded at Jordan Hall, Boston, Daniel Pinkham, conductor, Cambridge Records 1M/8/64, 1963, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Choral Triptych." 3 copies, one in mono and two in stereo)
    - "Admiral Byrd," 1960 December 5, (7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Produced by CBS The 20th Century. Music Only.)
    - "Admiral Bird," 1961 March13, (1 33 1/3 rpm acetate phonograph record) (Box 110)
      (Produced by CBS "The Twentieth Century")
    - American Composers Alliance (ACA) / Chamber Music Time (CMT) / Kay, 1960 November 6, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      Content of the reel has been digitized by Columbia University Libraries' Digital and Preservation Division, under the file name root: RBML_UlyssesKayPapers_7341105_WNYCChamberTime_19601106
      WNYC Chamber Time Featuring Ulysses Kay .The program featured the American Composers Alliance, with m.c. Don Jennings and Ulysses Kay as the featured composer.
    - American Composers Program Interview, WHIB, Chicago, 1986 January 7, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
    - "Aulos," 1971 February21, (7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      (For Solo Flute and Chamber Orchestra (first performance) from Benefit Recital, John Solum, flute, and Walter Robert, piano. Henry Charles Smith, conductor.)
    - Birthday Variations for Ulysses Kay, 1967, (1 5-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 108)
      (Birthday music composed for piano, four hands, from Kay’s "Suite for Strings" 2nd movement. Includes six variations composed by Slonimsky, Vincent, Cortes, Stevens, Dahl, and Kohs. Ingolf Dahl and Ramiro Cortes, pianists. See Also: Box 103, which contains the scores)
    - "The Black Composer in America" Oakland Youth Orchestra, Cynthia Bedford, mezzo-soprano, Robert Hughes, conductor, Desto Records DC 7107 circa 1970, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "A Short Overture")
    - Black Composers Series Volume 3, London Symphony Orchestra, Paul Freeman, conductor, Columbia, M 32783 1974, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Markings")
    - B’Nai B’Rith Memorial Concert, circa 1947, (2 acetate phonograph records; both discs have signs of deterioration) (Box 111)
    - Boston Interview for Premiere of "Presidential Suite," 1966, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
    - "Brief Elegy", undated, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
      (Roy Mueller, oboe)
    - Brevard Music Center (Former Composers) Symphonic Band, 1986 July 28, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
      (Includes Kay’s "Four Silhouettes")
    - "Capitoline Venus," undated, (2 7-inch reels, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
    - "Celebration in Song", 1984 March13 (Box 104)
      (Holland, Michigan)
    - Chapman College Symphony Orchestra #1, 1979 March10, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Includes "The Quiet One" and "Scherzi Musicali)
    - Chapman College Symphony Orchestra #2, 1979 March10, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Includes "Concerto for Orchestra" and "Markings." John Koshak, conductor.)
    - "Chariots," 1979, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      (Philadelphia Orchestra, Saratoga, New York)
    - "Chariots," 1980 April 15, (2 7-inch reels) (Box 114)
      (Performed by the Shreveport Symphony Orchestra, John Shenaut, conductor.)
    - "Chariots", 1984 October 1 (Box 104)
      (New York Philharmonic, Zubin Mehta, conductor)
    - "Choral Triptych," undated, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
    - Comm. Talk, 1967, (1 7-inch reel, 3 3/4 ips) (Box 106)
      Content of the reel has been digitized by Columbia University Libraries' Digital and Preservation Division, under the file name root: RBML_UlyssesKayPapers_7341105_KaySeminarForSCSC_19670000
      Kay Seminar for South Carolina State College (SCSC), 1967
    - Composer in Our Time: Ulysses Kay (WRVR), undated, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
    - The Contemporary Composer in the USA, Westphalian Symphony Orchestra, Recklinghausen, Paul Freeman, conductor, Turnabout TV-S 34546 1974, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Six Dances for Orchestra")
    - Composers Recordings, Inc., Oslo Philharmonic Orchestra, George Barati, conductor, Composers Recordings, Inc. CRI-139, 1958 or later, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Sinfonia in E")
    - Composers Recordings, Inc., Camarata and the New Symphony Orchestra of London, Composers Recordings, Inc. CRI-119, 1950s, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Round Dance and Polka for Strings")
    - Composers Recordings, Inc., Oslo Philharmonic Orchestra, Arthur Bennett Lipkin, conductor, Composers Recordings, Inc. CRI SD 209, circa 1965, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Fantasy Variations")
    - Contemporary American Composers, Teatro la Fenice Symphony Orchestra, John Perlea, conductor, Remington Records R-199-173, 1953, (1 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 109 A)
      (Includes Kay’s "Concerto for Orchestra." 3 copies)
    - Danse Calinda, undated, (1 5-inch reel) (Box 108)
      (For piano)
    - Death Essay Music, undated, (1 33 1/3 acetate phonographic record) (Box 110)
    - "Divertimento" / Brass Quartet, undated, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
    - "Essay on Death," 1964 November, (2 7-inch reels) (Box 106)
    - "Everett Suite," undated (Box 104)
      (Tom Everett, Brass Trombone)
    - Excerpts for Talk, 1973 November 25, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      Content of the reel has been digitized by Columbia University Libraries' Digital and Preservation Division, under the file name root: RBML_UlyssesKayPapers_7341105_ExcerptsForTalk
    - "Facets," 1971 October 19, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Peformed by Musica Nova)
    - "Fall of China," 1959 August 31, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips)
    - "Fall of China", undated, (1 33 1/3 acetate phonograph record. Record shows signs of deterioration) (Box 111)
      (Produced by Twentieth Century (Past).)
    - Family Tapes
      - Family Tape (Christmas), 1968, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      - Kids Speaking, 1964 May, (1 5-inch reel) (Box 108)
    - Fanfares by Kay and Britten, undated, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
      (Includes "Three Fanfares" (Kay) and "Fanfare for St. Edmundsbury" (Britten) )
    - "Fantasy Variations," 1963 November 19, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Performed by the Portland, Maine Symphony)
    - "Fantasy Variations" and "Umbrian Scene," circa 1963, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      ("Fantasy Variations" performed by the Portland, Maine Symphony and "Umbrian Scene" performed by the New Orleans Philharmonic)
    - "Fantasy Variations," 1974 September, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Performed by the Oakland Symphony Youth Orchestra in Berlin, Germany, Denis de Cobeau, conductor)
    - "FDR," 1958 March19, (1 33 1/3 rpm acetate phonograph record. Record shows signs of deterioration.) (Box 111)
      ([Produced by] Twentieth Century Past. See Also: "Roosevelt Show" on audio reel.)
    - Fisk University Film Music, undated, (1 5-inch reel) (Box 108)
      (Duplication of original music for "Fisk Film" "A Thing of Beauty")
    - Five Portraits for Violin and Piano," 1974 February22, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      (Coolidge Auditorium, Ruggiero Ricci, violin, and Leon Pommers, piano)
    - Five Winds: "Divertimento" Movements 1-4 (all), undated, (1 audiocassette, 13’07" in length) (Box 104)
    - "Forever Free," circa 1965, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 114)
      (Bill, New Jersey Civil War Centennial Commission, State House, Trenton, New Jersey. Washington DC Ceremony, outdoors.)
    - "Forever Free," 1967 March, (1 5-inch reel) (Box 108)
      (UCLA Band. Ulysses Kay, conductor.)
    - "Forever Free-A Lincoln Chronicle," undated, (1 10-inch acetate 33 1/3 rpm phonograph record) (Box 110)
    - "Four Inventions," 1970 April 23, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      (Ruth Slenczynska, piano recital at Karachi)
    - "The Game," 1963 January 8, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)
      (Contains two excerpts: Robbie’s Aria, "Change," and Leila’s Aria, "Maugeritus")
    - Green #1, 1984 May 26, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
      (University of Toledo. Includes "A New Song", "Two Dunbar Lyrics," "Forever Free," "Four Silhouettes," "Pieta for English Horn and Strings," "Of New Horizons,")
    - Haddonfield Symphony Orchestra, 1984 May 19, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
      (Includes Buck’s "Festival Overture on the National Air," Grieg’s "Concerto in A minro for Piano and Orchestra (Natalie Hinderas, solo piano), Kay’s "Presidential Suite," and Hanson’s "Symphony No. 1 in E Minor-‘Nordic’ ")
    - Harvard and McGill Wind Ensembles, 1988 March12, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
      (Includes "Heralds I," and "Forever Free")
    - Houston Symphony Orchestra, 1974 September, (1 7-inch reel, 7.5 ips) (Box 114)
      (Includes Kay’s "Three Pieces After Blake." Paul Freeman, conductor.)
    - "Interview - Black Music, Florida, undated, (2 7-inch reels, 7.5 ips) (Box 106)
      Content of the reel has been digitized by Columbia University Libraries' Digital and Preservation Division, under the file name root: RBML_UlyssesKayPapers_7341105_SketchOfBlackMusic
      "Sketch of Black Music" with Ulysses Kay, Florida Technological University University of Orlando.
    - "Jubilee," circa 1976, (5 7-inch reels) (Box 106)
    - "Jubilee" (Dorr) and Sermon (White), undated, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
    - "Jubilee" (Choral Chant) (Dorr) and "Essay 3" (Barber), undated, (1 audiocassette) (Box 104)
    - Untitled, undated, (1 7-inch reel) (Box 106)